wpcharitable.com 2018-09-22

# Privacy Policy | Charitable

This privacy policy was last updated on  **May 25, 2018**.

* * *

## Who we are

Our website address is https://www.wpcharitable.com.

This website is owned and operated by Studio 164a Pty Ltd (ACN 166 585 646).

We are committed to protecting your privacy as an online visitor to our website. We use the information we collect about you to maximize the services that we provide to you. We respect the privacy and confidentiality of the information provided by you and adhere to the Australian Privacy Principles. Please read our privacy policy below carefully.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

We will use all reasonable means to protect the confidentiality of your Personal Data while in our possession or control. We will not knowingly share any of your Personal Data with any third party other than our service providers who assist us in providing the information and/or services we are providing to you. To the extent that we do share your personal information with a service provider, we would only do so if that party has agreed to comply with our privacy standards as described in this privacy policy. Some of our service providers may be overseas and may not be subject to Australian Privacy Laws. Please read below for specific details about the personal data we may collect from you, why we collect it, how we store it and who we share it with.

Any non-personal information, communications and material you send to this website or to us by email, or which we obtain from third parties without promises of confidentiality, may be kept, used and disclosed by us on a non-confidential basis. We are free to use and reproduce any such information freely, and for any purpose whatsoever. Specifically, we will be free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how or techniques contained in such information for any purpose, including developing, manufacturing or marketing products.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service ([Gravatar privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/)) to see if you are using it. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Support form

When you contact us through our support form, we collect your name and email address, as well as your Charitable campaign URL and support message/question. This is required in order to receive and respond to your support and to help you get the most out of Charitable.

### Purchase form

We collect information about you during the checkout process on our store. This information may include, but is not limited to, your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and any other details that might be requested from you for the purpose of processing your orders.

Handling this data also allows us to:

– Send you important account/order/service information.  
– Respond to your queries, refund requests, or complaints.  
– Process payments and to prevent fraudulent transactions. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests.  
– Set up and administer your account, provide technical and/or customer support, and to verify your identity.

Additionally we may also collect the following information:

– Location and traffic data (including IP address and browser type) if you place an order, or if we need to estimate taxes and shipping costs based on your location.  
– Product pages visited and content viewed while your session is active.  
– Your comments and product reviews if you choose to leave them on our website.  
– Account email/password to allow you to access your account, if you have one.  
– If you choose to create an account with us, your name, address, and email address, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders.

### Newsletter signup form

When you complete the form to join our newsletter, we collect your first name and email address. This is required to subscribe you to our newsletter and personalize emails.

### Logs

The IP address of visitors, user ID of logged in users, and username of login attempts are conditionally logged to check for malicious activity and to protect the site from specific kinds of attacks. Examples of conditions when logging occurs include login attempts, log out requests, requests for suspicious URLs, changes to site content, and password updates. This information is retained for 14 days.

In addition, website traffic is monitored via SiteGround, which collects IP addresses that are saved for the duration of one month.

## How we use cookies on WP Charitable

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

We also use cookies to support the purchase process on WP Charitable. This includes but is not limited to storing products you have added to cart, coupons you have added and any VAT information you have provided in the checkout.

### Analytics

This website utilizes several tracking and analytics scripts (including but not limited to Google Analytics, Hotjar, Mixpanel and Facebook Tracking pixel), information is captured and then used to tailor a more targeted online experience.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Who we share your data with

We share your data with the following third parties:

 **Google** : We use Google Analytics to track your activity on our website. This allows us learn how people use our website, to improve our site experience and to market to you. Analytics tracks you anonymously unless you are logged into Google’s services. For more details, please see [Google’s terms and conditions.](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html)

 **Facebook** : We use the Facebook Pixel on our website to track user activity on WP Charitable, to improve the website experience and to market to you. Facebook tracks you personally if you are logged in to Facebook.

 **MailChimp** : If you join our newsletter list, your email address and name is stored in the MailChimp database, to allow us to send you personalized email newsletters.

 **Gravatar** : Your email address is shared in hashed form with the Gravatar service to see if you are using it and to display your Gravatar profile photo if you are. For more details, please see [Gravatar’s security policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

 **Sucuri** : This site is scanned for potential malware and vulnerabilities by Sucuri’s SiteCheck. We do not send personal information to Sucuri; however, Sucuri could find personal information posted publicly (such as in comments) during their scan. For more details, please see [Sucuri’s privacy policy](https://sucuri.net/privacy).

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

Security logs are retained for 14 days.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, have left comments, have made a purchase, have subscribed to our newsletter or have contacted us through our support form, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

https://www.wpcharitable.com is hosted on SiteGround.

We store database backups in Dropbox for up to two months.

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service named Akismet, operated by Automattic. (https://automattic.com/privacy/).

This site is part of a network of sites that protect against distributed brute force attacks. To enable this protection, the IP address of visitors attempting to log into the site is shared with a service provided by ithemes.com. For privacy policy details, please see the iThemes Privacy Policy (https://ithemes.com/privacy-policy).

The personal information we collect may be transferred to and stored in countries outside of the jurisdiction you are in where we and our third party service providers have operations. If you are located in the European Union (“EU”), your personal information will be processed outside of the EU including in Australia; these international transfers of your personal information are necessary for the performance of our agreement with you in order to provide the website and product.

## How we protect your data

We strive to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personal information submitted to our website, and we periodically update our security measures in light of current technologies.

## Disclosure of your information

We may from time to time need to disclose certain information, which may include your Personal Data, to comply with a legal requirement, such as a law, regulation, court order, subpoena, warrant, in the course of a legal proceeding or in response to a law enforcement agency request. Also, we may use your Personal Data to protect the rights, property or safety of https://www.wpcharitable.com, our customers or third parties.

If there is a change of control in one of our businesses (whether by merger, sale, transfer of assets or otherwise) customer information, which may include your Personal Data, could be disclosed to a potential purchaser under a confidentiality agreement. We would only disclose your information in good faith and where required by any of the above circumstances.

## Links to 3rd parties

This website may contain links to other websites. These links are meant for your convenience only. Links to third party websites do not constitute sponsorship or endorsement or approval of these websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage our users to be aware, when they leave our website, to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this website.

## Changes to this policy

As we plan to ensure our privacy policy remains current, this policy is subject to change. We may modify this policy at any time, in our sole discretion and all modifications will be effective immediately upon our posting of the modifications on this website. Please return periodically to review our privacy policy.

## Our contact information

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy, would like to request what personal data is held by us about you, or would like to request for your personal data to be erased, please contact our Data Protection Officer:

Eric Daams – privacy@wpcharitable.com
